RG 002:013, Engrossed Bills
Connecticut State Library
Engrossed bills
1859-1994
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. General Assembly
78 cubic feet
This subgroup is comprised of volumes of Engrossed Bills. Engrossed Bills are those legislative acts and resolutions that having been passed by the House of Representatives and the Senate are appropriately signed by the Engrossing Committee, Clerk of the Senate, President of the Senate, Clerk of the House, Speaker of the House, and the Governor.
RG002_013
T002461, 1986-008
Historical Note
Chapter II, section one and two of the Public Acts of 1859 specifies that the Secretary of the State upon the adjournment of the General Assembly shall cause all Engrossed Bills which have been signed and appropriately approved to be bound in a volume and shall record the same by title in the public records of the state. Thereafter, the bills shall be known as Public Acts passed by the General Assembly. Copies are to be made and certified by the Secretary of the State as copies of the record. Section six of the same chapter refers to the printing and distribution of Special Acts (called Private Acts prior to 1872) and resolutions by the Secretary of the State. These guidelines are similar to those of the Public Acts.
The General Assembly met annually until 1887. From 1889 to 1971 the Assembly met biannually. It has met annually since 1971.
Scope and Content
This subgroup is comprised of volumes of Engrossed Bills. Engrossed Bills are those legislative acts and resolutions that having been passed by the House of Representatives and the Senate are appropriately signed by the Engrossing Committee, Clerk of the Senate, President of the Senate, Clerk of the House, Speaker of the House, and the Governor. The requisite endorsement of the Governor coupled with two or more of the above signatures advances the Engrossed Act into law. The presence of the actual signatures indicates the original document. These original volumes have been certified and subsequent copies were produced. Duplicates of this series can be found at. Whereas this original series has no index the printed copies contain an index to each session of the Assembly.
Arrangement
The volumes are arranged chronologically. Between 1859 and 1878 the volumes are handwritten. The volume of bills for the session held in 1891 is missing.
The acts are arranged as follows: 1859 is arranged by the order in which the Engrossing Clerk prepared the documents for the Governor's signature; 1860-1861 arranged numerically by Public Act number and Private Act number (Arabic numerals), then chronologically by approval date (there are sporadic exceptions to this); 1862-1973 Public Acts are arranged by chapter number (1862-1889 chapter numbers are roman numerals, 1901 to present are Arabic numerals). The Acts are marked with their original bill number. Special Acts are arranged by Special Act number (Arabic numerals), then chronologically by approval date (there are sporadic exceptions to this). 1973 to 1994 Public Acts are arranged by a Public Act number which is made of the last two numbers of the year and an assigned number (example 84-105). These Acts are also marked with their original bill numbers. Special Acts are arranged similarly using the year and Special Act number. The original bill number also appears on the document.
Related Material
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. General Assembly
Subjects:
Bills, legislative -- Connecticut; Connecticut -- Politics and government
Document Types:
Bills (legislative records)
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Custodial History
The General Assembly submitted these records to the Office of the Secretary of the State, which subsequently transferred them to the Connecticut State Library. Accession T002461 contains Engrossed Bills, 1859-1972. All other former accessions dealing with Engrossed Bills and indices were combined into accession 1986-008.
The following accessions were combined into accession 1986-008:
Accession T001607 contained approval dates of Public and Special Acts, 1923-1950.
Accession T001608 contained index of Public and Special Acts, 1957-1961.
Accession T001580 contained indices of Preliminary and Unimportant records, 1936-1976.
Accession T001510 contained Engrossed Bills, 1973-1978 Public Acts part 1.
Accession 1985-030 was transferred to the State Library on November 25, 1985 and contained Engrossed Bills, 1978 Public Acts part 2; 1979-1982.
Accession 1986-008 was transferred to the State Library on March 7, 1986. It contained Engrossed Bills, 1983-1984 and indices of Preliminary and Unimportant records, 1977-1983.
Accession 1988-004 contained Engrossed Bills, 1978 Public Acts part 3; 1978 Special Acts part 1; 1985-1986.
Accession 1997-011 was transferred to the State Library on July 23, 1996. It contained Engrossed Bills, 1987 and indices of Preliminary and Unimportant records, 1984-1987.
Accession 1998-034 was transferred to the State Library on March 10, 1998. It contained Engrossed Bills, 1988-1990 and indices of Preliminary and Unimportant records, 1988-1990.
Accession 2007-011 contained Engrossed Bills, 1991-1994 and indices of Preliminary and Unimportant records, 1991-1994.
Inventory
- Series 1. Engrossed Bills, 1859-1994
  - T002461
    - Public Acts, 1859
    - Public/Special Acts, 1860
    - Public/Special Acts, 1861
    - Public/Special Acts, 1862
    - Public/Special Acts, 1863
    - Public/Special Acts, 1864
    - Public/Special Acts, 1865
    - Public/Special Acts, 1866
    - Public/Special Acts, 1867
    - Public/Special Acts, 1868
    - Private Acts, 1869
    - Public Acts, 1869
    - Public Acts, 1870
    - Private Acts, 1870
    - Private Acts, 1871
    - Public Acts, 1871
    - Special Acts, 1872
    - Public Acts, 1872
    - Public Acts, 1873
    - Special Acts, 1873
    - Special Acts, 1874
    - Public Acts, 1874
    - Public Acts, 1875
    - Special Acts, 1875
    - Public Acts, 1876
    - Special Acts, 1876
    - Special Acts, 1877
    - Public Acts, 1877
    - Public Acts, 1878
    - Special Acts, 1878
    - Public/Special Acts, 1879
    - Public/Special Acts, 1880
    - Public/Special Acts, 1881
    - Public/Special Acts, 1882
    - Public/Special Acts, 1883
    - Public/Special Acts, 1884
    - Public/Special Acts, 1885
    - Public/Special Acts, 1886
    - Public/Special Acts, 1887
    - Public/Special Acts, 1889
    - Public Acts, 1893
    - Special Acts, 1893
    - Special Acts, 1893
    - Public Acts, 1895
    - Special Acts, 1895
    - Special Acts, 1897
    - Public Acts, 1897
    - Special Acts, 1899
    - Public Acts, 1899
    - Special Acts, 1901
    - Public Acts, 1901
    - Special Acts, 1903
    - Public Acts, 1903
    - Public Acts, 1905
    - Special Acts, 1905
    - Public Acts, 1907
    - Special Acts, 1907
    - Public Acts, 1909
    - Special Acts, 1909
    - Public Acts, 1911
    - Special Acts, 1911
    - Public Acts, 1913
    - Special Acts, 1913
    - Public Acts, 1915
    - Special Acts, 1915
    - Public/Special Acts Special session, 1916 September
    - Public Acts, 1917
    - Special Acts, 1917
    - Public/Special Acts special session, 1918 March 19
    - Public/Special Acts special session, 1918 March 20
    - Public Acts, 1919
    - Special Acts, 1919
    - Public/Special Acts special session, 1920 September 14
    - Public/Special Acts Special session, 1920 September 21
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1921
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1921
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1921
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1921
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1923
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1923
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1923
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1923
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1925
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1925
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1925
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1925
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1925
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1927
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1927
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1927
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1927
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1927
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1929
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1929
    - Public Acts, part 2 Special session, 1929 August 6
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1929
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1929
    - Special Acts, part 2 special session, 1929 August 6
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1931
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1931
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1931
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1931
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1931
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1933
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1933
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1933
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1933
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1935
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1935
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1935
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1935
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1936 November 5
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1936 November 30
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1936 December 9
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1937
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1937
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1936 November 5
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1936 November 30
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1936 December 9
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1937
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1937
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1939
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1939
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1939
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1939
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1939
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1941
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1941
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1941
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1941
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1941
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1942 October 19
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1943
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1943
    - Public Acts, part 2 special session, 1944 January
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1942 October 19
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1943
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1943
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1943
    - Special Acts, part 3 special session, 1944 January
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1944 June
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1945
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1945
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1945
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1945
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1946 May
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1947
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1947
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1946 May
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1947
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1947
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1948 February
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1948 August
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1949
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1949
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1948 February
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1948 August
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1949
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1949
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1949 June
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1949 November
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1950 March
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1950 September
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1951
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1951
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1949 June
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1949 November
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1950 March
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1950 September
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1951
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1951
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1951
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1951 June
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1953
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1953
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1951 June
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1953
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1953
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1953
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1955
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1955
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1955
    - Public Acts, part 3 special session, 1955 June
    - Public Acts, part 3 special session, 1955 November
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1955
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1955
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1955
    - Special Acts, part 3 special session, 1955 June
    - Special Acts, part 3 special session, 1955 November
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1957
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1957
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1957
    - Public Acts, part 3 special session, 1957 September
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1957
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1957
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1957
    - Special Acts, part 3 special session, 1957 September
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1958 March
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1959
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1959
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1959
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1959
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1958 March
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1959
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1959
    - Special Acts, part 3, 1959
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1961
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1961
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1961
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1961
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1961
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1963
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1963
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1963
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1963
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1963 June
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1963
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1963
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1964 April
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1964 August
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1964 November
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1965
    - Public Acts, part 1 special session, 1965 February
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1965
    - Public Acts, part 2 special session, 1965 February
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1965
    - Public Acts, part 3 special session, 1965 February
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1965
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1965 February
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1965
    - Special Acts, part 2 special session, 1965 February
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1967
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1967
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1967
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1967
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1967
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1965 December
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1967
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1967
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1969
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1969
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1969
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1969
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1969 June
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1969
    - Special Acts, part 2, 1969
    - Special Acts, part 2 special session, 1969 June
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1971
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1971
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1971
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1971
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1971
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1971 June
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1971
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1971 June
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1972
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1972
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1972
    - Public Acts, part 3 special session, 1972 May
    - Public Acts, part 3 special session, 1972 June
    - Public Acts, part 3 special session, 1972 September
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1972
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1972 September
  - 1986-008
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1973
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1973
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1973
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1973
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1974
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1974
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1974
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1974
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1975
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1975
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1975
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1975
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1975 July
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1975 December
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1975
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1975 July
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1976
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1976
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1976
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1976
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1977
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1977
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1977
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1977
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1977
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1977
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1978
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1978
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1978
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1978
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1979
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1979
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1979
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1979
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1979 October
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1979
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1979 October
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1980
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1980
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1980
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1980
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1980
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1980
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1981
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1981
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1981
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1981
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1981
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1981 November
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1981
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1981 November
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1982
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1982
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1982
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1982
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1982
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1982 June
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1982
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1982 June
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1983
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1983
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1983
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1983
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1983
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1983 June
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1983
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1983 June
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1983 October
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1984
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1984
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1984
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1984
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1984
    - Public Acts, part 6, 1984
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1984
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1985
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1985
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1985
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1985
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1985
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1985 July
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1985
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1986
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1986
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1986
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1986
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1986 May
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1986 June 11
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1986 June 23
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1986
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1986 May
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1986 June 23
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1987
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1987
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1987
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1987
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1987
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1987 July
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1987
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1988
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1988
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1988
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1988
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1988
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1988
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1989
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1989
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1989
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1989
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1989
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1990
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1990
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1990
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1990
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1990 June
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1990
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1990 June
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 6, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 6 special session, 1991 June
    - Public Acts, part 7, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 7 special session, 1991 June
    - Public Acts, part 8, 1991
    - Public Acts, part 8 special session, 1991 June 12
    - Public Acts, part 8 special session, 1991 June 26
    - Public Acts, part 8 special session, 1991 November
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1991
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1991 June
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1992
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1992
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1992
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1992
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1992 May
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1992 June
    - Public Acts, part 4 special session, 1992 June 29
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1992
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1992 May
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1993
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1993
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1993
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1993
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1993
    - Public Acts, part 6, 1993
    - Public Acts, part 6 special session, 1993 June
    - Public Acts, part 6 special session, 1993 July
    - Public Acts, part 6 special session, 1993 September
    - Public Acts, part 6 special session, 1993 October
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1993
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1993 June
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1993 October
    - Public Acts, part 1, 1994
    - Public Acts, part 2, 1994
    - Public Acts, part 3, 1994
    - Public Acts, part 4, 1994
    - Public Acts, part 5, 1994
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1994 May
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1994 May 25
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1994 July
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1994 July 13
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1994 October
    - Public Acts, part 5 special session, 1994 November
    - Special Acts, part 1, 1994
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1994 May 25
    - Special Acts, part 1 special session, 1994 November
- Series 2. Indices, 1923-1994; 1986-008
  - Approval dates of Public and Special Acts, 1923-1950; 1 volume
  - Index of Public and Special Acts, 1957-1961; 1 volume
  - Index of Preliminary and Unimportant records, 1936-1950, 1957-1994; 25 volumes
    Indices for years 1977-1994 are stored among the Public and Special Acts at the end of each proper year.